A Guide to the Blake W. Corson, Jr., Papers, 1861-1984 (Bulk, 1934-1979)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Blake W. Corson, Jr., Papers,1861-1984 (Bulk, 1934-1979)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Corson, Blake W., Jr.
Ms1990-055
17.7 Cubic Feet 9 boxes; 17 folders
The Blake W. Corson, Jr., Papers are comprised of professional and personal files, correspondence, and published materials from 1861-1984 (bulk, 1934-1979), primarily relating to his career as an engineer at NASA Langley.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Blake W. Corson, Jr., Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1990.
Biographical Historical Note
Family History
Blake Wilson Corson was born in Cumberland Virginia In 1874. Wilson Corson had five sisters. Corson attended Virginia Polytechnic Institute in 1895. Corson married Anne Mason "Annie" White on April 23, 1907. Blake Wilson Corson, Jr., was born to Blake Wilson Corson (1874-1962) and Anne Mason Corson (1874-1968) on October 1st in 1908 in Henrico, Virginia. Corson had two youngers sisters Juidith Parker (born July 20, 1911) and Georgina White (born June 26, 1915). Blake W. Corson, Jr. married Shirley Huxter (1921-2014) on December 6, 1947. They had one daughter. Corson, Jr.'s father died in 1962. Blake Wilson Corson was buried with Grace Episcopal Church. Anne Corson died in 1968; she was buried next to her spouse. Blake W. Corson, Jr., died at 83 on December 23, 1991. He was survived by his wife and daughter. Corson was burried in Peninsula Memorial Park Newport News. Shirley Corson died in 2014 at the age of 93.
Education and Work
Blake W. Corson, Jr., graduated from John Marshall High School. Corson, Jr., attended the University of Richmond and earned a B.S. in Mathmatics and Physics in 1932. In 1935 Corson, Jr., began working with the National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics and the Natioanl Aeronautical and Space Association. Corson, Jr., retired in 1972.
Degrees and Universities
University of Richmond, B.S. Mathmatics
University of Richmond, B.S. Physics
Patents
Cascade Plug Nozzle, Filed :1974, 07, 12, Publication: 1976, 02, 17
Nozzle: Filed: 1960, 05, 23; Publication: 1961,12,12
Publications
"The Aerodynamics of a Wind Tunnel Fan." NASA. 1941.
"Model Tests of a Wing-Duct System for Auxiliary Air Supply." NASA. 1941.
"The Belt Method for Measuring Pressure Distribution." NASA. 1943.
"Cooling Characteristics of a Pratt and Whitney R-2800 Engine Installed in an NACA Short-nose High-inlet-velocity Cowling." NASA. 1944.
"Analysis of Propeller Efficiency Losses Associated with Heated-air Thermal De-icing." NASA. 1946.
"The Effect of Simulated Icing on Propeller Performance." NASA. 1946.
"Investigation of the Effect of a Tip Modification and Thermal De-icing Air Flow on Propeller Performance." NASA. 1946.
"A Review Of Propeller Theory" NASA. 1948.
"The Langley 2,000 Horsspower propeller Dynamometer and Tests at High Speed of an NACA 10-(3)(08)-03 Two Blade Propeller". NASA. 1952.
"Static Thrust of an Annular Nozzle with a Concave Central Base." NASA. 1960.
"Transonic Thrust and Drag Characteristics of an Annular Nozzle Having a Semitoroidal Concave Plug." NASA. 1964.
"Summary of Research on Jet Exit Installations." NASA. 1966.
"Calibration of the Langley 16-Foot Transonic Tunnel with Test Section Air Removal." NASA. 1974.
SOURCES:
http://articles.dailypress.com/1991-12-25/news/9112240222_1_nephews-and-cousins-mr-corson-suffolk-christian-church
http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&GSln=Corson&GSfn=Blake&GSmn=Wilson&GSiman=1&GSby=1874&GSbyrel=in&GSdy=1962&GSdyrel=in&GSst=48&GSob=n&GRid=5313978&df=all&
http://www.findagrave.net/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&GRid=83447647
Ancestry.com Library Edition
Scope and Content
The Blake W. Corson Jr., Papers are comprised of professional and personal files, correspondence, and published materials from 1861-1984 (bulk, 1934-1979), primarily relating to his career as an engineer at NASA Langley. Topics include aerodynamic performance of aircraft propellers and manned aircraft; wind tunnel fans, jet noise suppression, and tunnel calibration. This collection is organized into five series by material type.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into five series by material type.
Series I: Personal Papers, 1861-1865, 1962-1966, n.d. includes Corson's resume, personal photographs, and materials relating to the Corson family history, genealogy, and copies of family correspondence. This series is arranged by material type.
Series II: Personal Projects, 1941-1979, n.d. consists of research, subject files, patent forms, and extensive notes on a variety of research projects conducted by Corson outside of his work for Langley. The majority of this series surrounds two projects: "Toward Energy Independence" and Corson's interest in environmental clean up in the Newport News area. This series is arranged by project/topic.
Series III: Correspondence/Memorandum, 1938-1978, n.d. contains letters to and from a variety of scientists, researchers, community members, government employees, and some corporations and agencies. In addition, there are extensive memos written reporting on projects of which Corson was a part. There is a list of major correspondents below. This series in in chronological order.
Major correspondents in this collection include:
A.W. Vogley
Abe Silverstien
Acoustics Division (Position Transfer)
Admiral Ralph W. Cousins (Cleaning Up Newport News)
Anita Cavagnara Associate Director (Cooperation and Research with Boeing)
Bill Greathoose Booth (High Speed Tunnel)
Chief Of Aerodynamics (High Speed Tunnel Reports)
Chief of Compressibility Research (16ft High Speed Tunnel Rotating Seal)
Chief of Compressibility Research (Project Z)
Chief of Research (Mechanical Sink)
Chief of Research (Propeller Projects and Papers)
Chief of Research (Thermal Deiceing Propeller and Jet Driven Propeller)
Clyde Lumpkin Construction Office, John D.R. Zeno (ASME Talk on Propeller Theory)
David Biermann (Moffett Field/Langley Field Fans, R-2800 Engine)
Director John R. Erwin (Shadow Graph Wing Shock)
Donald D. Amos (Oscillating Orfice Pump)
Donald D. Baals
Dr. Adolph Busemann
Dr. Clinton C. Kemp E. Boxer (Compressor Noise Reduction)
E. J. Manganilleo E. Johnson (Moffett Field Fans)
Edgar M. Cartright Energy Research and Development Administration Engineer in Charge (High Speed Tunnel)
Engineer in Charge (Servo Control) FAECT-- PAC Committee of Chapter 15
Frank Smiley (Newport News City Manager)
G.W. Lewis
George R. Kinney
H. J. E. Reid
H.B. Edwards (16 foot Wind Tunnel Fan Blades)
Hamilton Standard Division
Harleth G. Wiley (Research and Technology Resume Numbering System)
Harry E. Shanner
Henry Balfour
Howard J. Osborn; Office of Patent Council LRC (Mutiple Cell Toridal Vortex Tube)
Hugh L. Dryden (University Conference on Aerodynamics)
J. G. McHugh
J.M. Carson, Jr. (Office Patent Council)
J.O. Tresansky (Office Patent Council)
J.W. Crowly
James B. Delanor
John L. Crigler
John N. Randolph (Patent, Improved Type of Crate for Bottled Beverages)
John V. Becker (Moffett Field Tunnel Fans)
Keffer (Langley Field Rear Propeller)
L. R. Quarles (Blade Elements)
Lawrence K. Loftin, Jr. (McDonnel Douglas Review)
Leland B. Salters, Jr.
Lindsey I. Turner (Oscillating Orfice Pump)
Lowell Hasel
Manned Spacecraft Center
Mark R. Nichols (VTOL, FSRD)
Mason (16 ft Wind Tunnel Study and Alteration)
Mason (Gust Tunnel)
Messick (Langley Field Rear Fan)
Michael A. Chaszeyka (McDonnel Douglas Review)
Mr. DeFraue (Two Dimensional Pressure Tunnel)
Mr.Wood (Free-Flight Tunnel)
NACA/LMAL Travel Permission
Norman Silvers
P.W. Mangen (Hotel New Yorker)
Paul Taynton (Texaco; Hydrazine in Fuel)
Peninsula Planning District Commission (Cleaning Up Newport News)
Planning Office of the Technical Service Division
President Jimmy Carter (Energy Crisis)
R.C. Platt
R.J. Landberg (McDonnell Douglas Review)
Ray W. Hooker (Gust Tunnel)
Ribner
Richard O. Carden
Robert R. Gilruth
S. Walter Hixton Jr. (Management Training)
State Corporation Commission
Sylvia Thomas (S.A.E.)
Tab Smith (York County Board of Supervisors)
Travel Request and Authorization U.S. Office of Patents (Purox System)
Union Carbide Corporation (Cleaning up Newport News/ Towards Energy Independence)
William A. Harding
William A. Scheller
Series IV: Professional Projects, 1937-1984, n.d. includes a small group of outlines and reports. This series primarily consist of five subseries, organized by topic/project, consisting of a variety of formats from Corson's work as an Aerospace Engineer with NASA. Subseries A: Research Tunnels includes papers and research relating to a variety of tunnels on which Corson worked (other than the 16 foot Transonic Tunnel (which is its own subseries below). Subseries B: Propellers and Propeller Research includes notes, graphs, calculations, and subject files on propellers and fan designs. Subseries C: Nozzles and Nozzle Research includes reports, notes, figures, proposals, and designs for nozzles. Subseries D: Research Projects contains drawings, calculations, notes, and subject files on topics relating to aspects of flight and engineering, especially certain parts or processes. Subseries E: 16 Foot Transonic Tunnel and Research includes extensive notes, photographs, calculations, notes, and reports on one of Corson's major projects and research topics. Materials in these series, subseries, and sub-subseries are organized by topic/subject.
Major projects in this series include:
19 Foot Pressure Tunnel
20 Spin Tunnel
AERL Ice Tunnel
Air Breathing Propulsions Systems
Annular Nozzle with a Concave Central base
Annular Nozzle with a Semi Toridal Base
Carderock Wind Tunnel
Cascade Plug Nozzle
Convergent Divergent Nozzle
Exhaust Nozzle and Jet Nozzle Performance
High Speed Tunnel
Jet Interference Program
McDonnell Douglas Review
Moffett Field
Perforated Diffuser Nozzle Bifurcated Rotary Joint
Propeller Research Tunnel
Stability Tunnel
Swept Wing
Transonic Tunnel
Two Dimensional Pressure Tunnel
Series V: Publications, Journals, and Reports, 1934-1982 contains published works by Corson or collected by him for research purposes. The majority are directly related to projects on which Corson worked. This series includes six subseries, organized by type of publication (Publications, Reports, Papers, Journals, Articles, and Pamphlets, Brochures, and Directories). Materials in each subseries are organized alphabetically by title.
Index Terms
Persons:
Becker, John Vernon, 1913- -- Correspondence; Bierman, David -- Correspondence
Subjects:
Archives of American Aerospace Exploration (AAAE); Physics; Science and Technology; United States. National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration
Genre and Form Term:
Blueprints; Correspondence; Engineering Drawings; Memorandums
Occupations:
Aeronautical engineers; Physicists; United States. National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics -- Officials and employees; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration -- Officials and employees
Contents List
- Series I: Personal Papers, 1861-1865, 1962-1966, n.d.
  Civil War; Family histories
  - Resume, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs--Corson, 1962-1966, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Subseries A: Family History and Letter Copies
    - "My Dear Jennie"--Author: William Clark Corson; Editor: Blake W. Corson, Jr., 1861-1865 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "My Dear Jennie"--1861 Letters; Correspondence-- William Clark Corson, Jennie, 1861, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "My Dear Jennie"--1862 Letters; Correspondence-- William Clark Corson, Jennie, 1862, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "My Dear Jennie"--1863 Letters; Correspondence-- William Clark Corson, Jennie, 1863, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "My Dear Jennie"--1864 Letters; Correspondence-- William Clark Corson, Jennie, 1864, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "My Dear Jennie"--1865 Letters; Correspondence-- William Clark Corson, Jennie; Closing Quote, 1865, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II: Personal Projects, 1941-1979, n.d.
  Aeronautics; Aerospace engineers; Photographs; Aircraft
  - VT Bomb Fuse, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Practice Problems--Least of Squares, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Proposal Outlining the Feasibility of Humans in Space --Notes/Data, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Patent Forms--NAVEXOS, 1951, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Materials from this sub-series are in Box 1 (folders listed below) and in oversize Folder 1.
    - "Towards Energy Independence"-- Research, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Towards Energy Independence"--Research Notes, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Inter Technology Corporation--"The Enerfy Plantation" (Cr. Clinton C. Kemp), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Professional Engineer--"Energy from Municipal Refuse a Comparison of 10 Processes," Ca. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - U.S. News and World Report--Issue February 14 1977; pg 23-26, 63-66, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Towards Energy Independence"--Notes/Proposal Draft, 1977, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Towards Energy Independence"--Proposal Draft, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Towards Energy Independence"--Proposal Final, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Towards Energy Independence", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - The Virginia Engineer--Volume 27, Number 8 (Two Copies), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Subseries B: Cleaning Up Newport News (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Cleaning Up Newport News"/ "Towards Energy Independence"--Tables/Maps/Figures, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Union Carbide--Purox System: Fuel Gas Characteristics, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Union Carbide--Purox System: Waste Resource Recovery, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Correspondence
    - Notes on Purox Patent, 1975, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Union Carbide--The Purox System (T.F. Fisher, M.L. Kasbohm, J.R. Rivero), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Union Carbide--"The Production of Industrial Gases from Air" (R.L. Shaner), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Union Carbide-- "Linde Molecular Sieves," 1976 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Union Carbide-- "Purox System Charecteristics," 1976 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Union Carbide--"Molecular Sieves in the Process Industries", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Times Herald--Articles on Cleaning Up Newport News (by BWC), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - "Look Ahead Newpport News"--Research/Notes, 1977, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Origional Text--"Look Ahead Newport News," (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - "Look Ahead Newport News" -- Proposal Draft, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - "Look Ahead Newport News," 1977 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Times Herald--Newport News Waste, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - "Abolish The Dung Heaps"-- Draft, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "Abolish The Dung Heaps," 1978 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Reflective Beam--Calculations/Sketches, 1979, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Series III: Correspondence/ Memorandum, 1938-1978, n.d.
  Memorandums; Aeronautics; Correspondence; Langley Aeronautical Laboratory
  - Correspondence--Mason (Gust Tunnel), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence--Construction Office, John, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Memorandum--Mr. DeFraue (Two Dimensional Pressure Tunnel), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence-- H. J. E. Reid, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence-- G.W. Lewis and R.C. Platt, 1938, Ca.1970 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Memorandum--Mr.Wood (Free-Flight Tunnel), 1939 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Memorandum--Chief Of Aerodynamics (High Speed Tunnel Reports), 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence-- FAECT-- PAC Committee of Chapter 15, 1941-1943, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Memorandum-- Engineer in Charge (Servo Control), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Memorandum-- For Files (Pressure Belt Analysis), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence--Mason (16 ft Wind Tunnel Study and Alteration), Ca. 1942 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Memorandum-- Messick (Langley Field Rear Fan), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Memorandum--Keffer (Langley Field Rear Propeller), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Memorandum-- E. Johnson (Moffett Field Fans), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence--L. R. Quarles (Blade Elements), 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Memorandum-- David Biermann (Moffett Field/Langley Field Fans, R-2800 Engine), 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Memorandum-- H.B. Edwards (16 foot Wind Tunnel Fan Blades), 1943 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Memorandum-- J.W. Crowly, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence--Planning Office of the Technical Service Division, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Memorandum-- Ray W. Hooker (Gust Tunnel), 1943 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Memorandum--Chief of Compressibility Research (16ft High Speed Tunnel Rotating Seal), 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Memorandum--Booth (High Speed Tunnel), 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Memorandum-- Engineer in Charge ( High Speed Tunnel), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Memorandum-- John V. Becker (Moffett Field Tunnel Fans), 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Memorandum-- Clyde Lumpkin, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Memorandum/Photos--Chief of Research (Thermal Deiceing Propeller and Jet Driven Propeller), 1944 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Memorandum--Chief of Research (Propeller Projects and Papers), 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence--Bill Greathoose, 1944, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence--Unidentified, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence--A.W. Vogley, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence-- John L. Crigler, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence--J. G. McHugh, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence--Ribner, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence-- James B. Delanor, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence/Notes--NACA/LMAL Travel Permission, 1945-1957 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Memorandum-- Chief of Compressibility Research (Project Z), 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Memorandum--J.P.L. Appendix, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Memorandum-- Chief of Research (Mechanical Sink), 1946 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Memorandum-- Personal Request, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Memorandum-- Dr. Adolph Busemann, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Memorandum-- Director John R. Erwin (Shadow Graph Wing Shock) (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Correspondence-- Sylvia Thomas (S.A.E.), 1947 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Correspondence-- Hugh L. Dryden (University Conference on Aerodynamics), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Correspondence-- Henry Balfour, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence-- P.W. Mangen (Hotel New Yorker), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Correspondence-- D.R. Zeno (ASME Talk on Propeller Theory), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence -- Anita Cavagnara, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Memorandum-- Changes to the Full Scale Research Division, 1949-1962 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Correspondence-- John N. Randolph ( Patent, Improved Type of Crate for Bottled Beverages ), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Memorandum-- Robert R. Gilruth, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Correspondence-- E. J. Manganilleo, Abe Silverstien, Lewis, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Correspondence--Norman Silvers, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Memorandum-- Acoustics Division (Position Transfer), 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Correspondence--J.O. Tresansky; J.M. Carson, Jr. (Office Patent Council), 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Memorandum--Editorial Review of "Static Thrust of an Annular Jet Exit with a Concave Base," 1960 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Correspondence-- Paul Taynton (Texaco; Hydrazine in Fuel), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Memorandum-- Associate Director (Cooperation and Research with Boeing), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Memorantum-- Manned Spacecraft Center, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Correspondence/Forms--Travel Request and Authorization, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Corresponcence-- Howard J. Osborn; Office of Patent Council LRC (Mutiple Cell Toridal Vortex Tube), 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Memorandum-- Donald D. Baals, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Memorandum-- S. Walter Hixton Jr. (Management Training), 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Correspondence-- Hamilton Standard Division, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Memorandum--Mark R. Nichols (VTOL, FSRD), 1966, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Memorandum-- Program Changes (FSRD), 1967, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Correspondence--E. Boxer (Compressor Noise Reduction), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Memorandum-- Lindsey I. Turner (Oscillating Orfice Pump), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Memorandum-- Donald D. Amos (Oscillating Orfice Pump), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Correspondence-- Michael A. Chaszeyka, Lawrence K. Loftin, Jr. (McDonnel Douglas Review), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Correspondence -- R.J. Landberg (McDonnell Douglas Review) (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Correspondence--Harry E. Shanner, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Correspondence--George R. Kinney, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Correspondence-- Harleth G. Wiley (Research and Technology Resume Numbering System), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Correspondence--Lowell Hasel, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Memorandum--Leland B. Salters, Jr., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Correspondence/Contracts/Reciepts-- Salters, 1973, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Correspondence--Union Carbide Corporation (Cleaning up Newport News/ Towards Energy Independence), 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Correspondence-- Edgar M. Cartright, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - Correspondence-- Dr. Clinton C. Kemp, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Correspondence--U.S. Office of Patents (Purox System), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - Correspondence-- William A. Scheller, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Correspondence--Peninsula Planning District Commission (Cleaning Up Newport News), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Correspondence-- William A. Harding, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Correspondence-- Richard O. Carden, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Correspondence--President Jimmy Carter (Energy Crisis), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Correspondence-- Frank Smiley ( Newport News City Manager), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - Correspondence-- Admiral Ralph W. Cousins (Cleaning Up Newport News), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - Correspondence--Energy Research and Development Administration, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Correspondence--Tab Smith (York County Board of Supervisors), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - Correspondence--State Corporation Commission, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 130)
- Series IV: Professional Projects, 1937-1984, n.d.
  Reports; Aerospace engineers; Notes; Engineering Drawings
  - Management Training--Outlines/Reports, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - Subseries A: Research Tunnels (Folder 10, Folder 12, Folder 13, Folder 14, Folder 15, Folder 16, Folder 17)
    Materials from this sub-series are in Box 1 (folders listed below) and in oversize Folders 10-17.
    - 7' by 10' Wind Tunnel--Obsolete Propeller Design, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 132)
    - Sub-subseries i: AERL Deicing (Folder 11)
      Materials from this sub-subseries are in Box 1 (folders listed below) and in oversize Folder 11.
      - "The Effect of Ice and Heated-Air Deicing on the Aerodynamic Performance of Propellers" (Transparet Report), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 133)
      - "The Effect of Ice and Heated-Air Deicing on the Aerodynamic Performance of Propellers" --Report, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 134)
      - "The Effect of Ice and Heated-Air Deicing on the Aerodynamic Performance of Propellers" (Figures), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 135)
      - AERL Ice Tunnel--Countervanes, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 136)
      - AERL Ice Tunnel -- Propellers, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 137)
      - AERL Ice Tunnel-- Estimation of Air State of Fan (Drawings/Notes), 1942, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 138)
      - AERL Ice Tunnel-- Propellers (Calculations/Notes), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 139)
      - AERL Ice Tunnel-- Countervane Design Analysis (Calculations/Notes), 1943, 1967, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 140)